Guide to the Kerry Stowell/Watergate East, Inc. papers, 1988-2011 MS2299
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Kerry Stowell/Watergate East, Inc. papers
1988-2011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Stowell, Kerry H.
MS2299
3 Linear Feet
This collection contains newsletters, photographs, correspondence, annual reports, and governing documents created and gathered by Kerry Stowell as a member of the co-op board of Watergate East, Incorporated. The material dates from 1988 to 2011.
Biographical / Historical
The Watergate East apartment building was built in 1965 and is located at 2500 and 2510 Virginia Avenue, NW in Washington. It is part of a complex that also includes the Watergate Hotel and office complex that was the site of the infamous 1972 break-in. The Watergate Complex is listed on the National Register of Historic Places.
Kerry Stowell is a resident of Watergate East, a member of the co-op board of Watergate East, Incorporated (WEI), an amateur photographer, and the editor of the residents' newsletter.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Kerry H. Stowell, 2011 (Accession 2011.079)
Scope and Contents
This collection contains newsletters, photographs, correspondence, annual reports, and governing documents created and gathered by Kerry Stowell as a member of the co-op board of Watergate East, Incorporated. The material dates from 1988 to 2011.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Watergate East newsletters; Photographs; and Watergate East Board of Directors
Buildings -- Washington (D.C.); Stowell, Kerry H.
- Watergate East newsletters, 1991-1998; Series 1; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains newsletters for and about the residents of the Watergate East co-op that were edited by Stowell from 1991-1998. Newsletters featured articles on building policies, short biographies of residents and staff, recipes, neighborhood news, and residents' questions about the day-to-day functioning of the co-op.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Watergate Post, 1988-1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Watergate Post, 1993-1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Floppy disks, 1991-2002; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Watergate Post floppy disks, 1994; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Photographs, 1988-2007; Series 2; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains photographs and thumbnail printouts of photographs of Watergate exteriors and individuals, images that in many cases were used for the Watergate East newsletters. They date from 1988-2007. This series also contains a photo book entitled "Watergate East Anniversary Issue 1964-1992" including many photos taken by Stowell.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Channel 99 cable channel images, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Foggy Bottom News photographs, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Snapshots of individuals at local political events, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Thumbnail images of Watergate, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Watergate East photographs, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Watergate Post photographs, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Watergate Outside book and postcards, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Watergate East Anniversary Issue 1964-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Watergate East 1965-2011 photo book (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Watergate East Board of Directors, 1992-2011; Series 3; 2.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains correspondence, memoranda, meeting agendas and minutes, annual reports and governing documents from the Watergate East, Incorporated (WEI) co-op board. The material dates from 1992-2011. This series also includes materials relating to the 2004 acquisition of the Watergate Hotel by Monument Realty, as well as materials relating to the effort to put the Watergate complex on the National Register of Historic Places.
  - Application for Historic Landmark Status, 2004-2005; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Committee to Preserve the Watergate Heritage [1 of 2], 2005; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Committee to Preserve the Watergate Heritage [2 of 2], 2005; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Copies of newspaper clippings on the Watergate, 1963-1965; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and proposals for janitorial services, 2008; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Foggy Bottom News, 1991; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Historic Preservation Review Board, 2004; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History of the Watergate (DVD) with Mario di Valmorana and The Watergate (DVD) by Monument Realty, 08 December 2005; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - In re: Monument's Push to Eliminate Watergate Hotel, undated; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Kennedy Center, 2004; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stowell biographical information, undated; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Watergate Complex Council, 2006; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Vote Stowell, 1994; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Watergate East Cooperative, Proposal for Condition Assessment, 2008; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Watergate East security, 2006; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Watergate/Monument Realty [1 of 3], 2004; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Watergate/Monument Realty [2 of 3], 2004; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Watergate/Monument Realty [3 of 3], 2004; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Watergate Anniversary Issue Upgrade [1 of 2], 2005-2006; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Watergate Anniversary Issue Upgrade [2 of 2], 2005-2006; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Insurance proposal, 2010; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - WEI Annual Meeting, 2006; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - WEI Annual Report, 2005; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - WEI Annual Report, 2006; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - WEI Annual Report, 2010; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - WEI audit, 1991; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda, 1992; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda [1 of 3], 2004; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda [2 of 3], 2004; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda [3 of 3], 2004; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda, 2006; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda [1 of 3], 2007-2009; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda [2 of 3], 2007-2009; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda [3 of 3], 2007-2009; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - WEI board correspondence and memoranda, 2010-2011; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - WEI Board candidates, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - WEI Board meetings, 2010; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - WEI Board nominees, 2005; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - WEI button, 2004; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - WEI By-laws, 2007; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - WEI Capital Improvements Program, 2006; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - WEI Governing documents, 2006; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - WEI membership committee, 2007; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - WEI membership committee, 2008-2010; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Watergate news clips (DVD), 17 June 2002; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - WEI rules and by-laws, 2004; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Zoning Commission Public Hearing, Watergate Hotel, 2004; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 12)